

# TRISTAN SCOTT

256-493-0366 | TSCOTT96@LIVE.COM | TRISTAN-SCOTT.COM 500 WEBSTER ROAD, LOT 342, AUBURN AL 36832

# **EDUCATION**

B.S. SOFTWARE ENGINEERING AUBURN UNIV. • 2015 – PRESENT

- SOA scholarship recipient (full tuition)
- Dean's list 2016
- Co-Op work program
- Graduating May 2020

# **PROJECTS**

#### TIA REST API

 Project lead for developing REST Web API for the Transportation Intermediaries Association's online data collection web application as part of Co-Op capstone project.

#### **BIG BLUE MARBLE**

 Responsible for overseeing transition of 30+ daycare centers to new management. Provided full IT assessments, reports, and migration. Provided full network inspections, overhauls and installations.

#### WATSON PIZZA (IN PROGRESS)

 Currently working as part of a fourmember team on a virtual agent pizza ordering system using IBM's Watson Assistant. Working with an IBM sponsor to setup web services that interact with Watson to accept pizza orders over telephone.

## **SUMMARY**

Upcoming BSSE graduate from Auburn University with over two years of full stack web development experience. A fast learner with a friendly demeanor, a passion for problem solving, and a constant desire to expand his skillsets and knowledge. Looking to join a skilled development team and kickstart his career in software engineering.

## **EXPERIENCE**

DEVELOPER / CONSULTANT • UNCONFUSING TECH. • JUNE 2017 – SEPT. 2019

Part of three-man operation that serviced over 150 concurrent entities.

- Full stack web development using PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL and JS
- On-site and remote IT support technician and consultant
- Project manager for several IT and software projects
- Includes one year of full-time Co-Op work experience

SALES ASSOCIATE • ACADEMY SPORTS • FEB. 2016 – MAY 2017

Footwear sales associate and part-time member of freight team.

- Communicated with customers to fulfill their needs
- Maintained a well-organized department
- Coordinated with footwear team to meet sales goals

IT INTERNSHIP • TGL COMMUNICATIONS • AUG. 2015 – DEC. 2015

Consultant in small scale IT firm servicing automotive suppliers.

- On-site tech support for offices and manufacturing plants
- Monitored servers, firewalls, and other critical systems

# SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

Languages: Java, C++, Python, PHP, JavaScript, SQL

Frameworks: Codelgniter, Materialize, Bootstrap, JQuery, Swing, JUnit, PyGame

APIs: Google Maps, AWS, IBM Watson, RESTful Development

Platforms: Windows, MacOS, Linux

**Networking:** Systems Administration, LAN Installation, LAN Configuration

Creative: Adobe CC, Blender, CAD

Other: Technical Documentation, UML Diagramming, System Diagramming







